warbyparker.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy | Warby Parker

## Privacy Policy

## Effective Date: August 23, 2019

At Warby Parker, we’re all about helping you see things a little more clearly. And we believe that you have a right to know what information we collect from you and how we protect your privacy. So we’ve created this Privacy Policy to let you know what to expect when you interact with us. This Privacy Policy applies to your use of our retail locations, as well as any of our websites, website features, and mobile applications (each, an “App”) that contain a link to this Privacy Policy. 

We operate a mobile application and related website (the “Prescription Check App”) and retail store service and related website (“In-Store Prescription Check” and, together with the Prescription Check App, “Prescription Check”) that you may use for the purpose of performing a vision test that may allow you to update your eyewear prescription. We also operate MyVisionDirectory, located at [www.myvisiondirectory.com](https://www.myvisiondirectory.com/), which is a website that you may use to search for and book eye exams (“MyVisionDirectory”). This Privacy Policy applies to your use of Prescription Check and MyVisionDirectory. Collectively the retail locations, our websites and Apps, Prescription Check, and MyVisionDirectory are referred to in this Privacy Policy as the “Services”. 

Your use of Prescription Check is subject to our Prescription Check Terms of Use. Your use of all other Services is subject to our Terms of Use. Our use of any individually identifiable health information you provide is subject to the requirements of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (“HIPAA”). In addition to this Privacy Policy, our Notice of Privacy Practices will apply to such information. 

By using our Services, you agree to the collection, use, disclosure, and procedures this Privacy Policy describes. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to third party websites (“Third Party Services”), such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Instagram, Snapchat, and Google+, that we do not own or control, even if you access them through our Services. We try to work only with Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, but we cannot take responsibility for their practices, content, or privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access so that you know how they will collect, use, and share your information.

If you have any questions, please reach out to us at [privacy@warbyparker.com](mailto:privacy@warbyparker.com).

## 1\. What Information does Warby Parker Collect

 **Information you provide us:**

  *  **When you create an account.** When you create an account with us, you provide a name, email address, and password. 

  * **When you make a purchase or use our Services.** If you make a purchase, we request information from you to facilitate the transaction and get you the goods. You may also provide us with information when you use certain online features, such as Home Try-On or when you book an eye exam. This information may include (i) your name, email address, phone number, shipping address, and date of birth, (ii) prescription information, including any images of prescriptions you may provide to us and any information you give us through the pupillary distance measurement function of our Services, (iii) medical history and information about your vision, (iv) information about the products you try on and purchase, and (v) information about other people, such as when you direct us to send a gift card. If you provide us with an image of your prescription, we obtain any information that appears on the prescription form. You may also provide us with information when you apply for a job through our Jobs page. 

For some online, App, and in-store features, we may ask you to submit (or we may ask your permission to take) a photo, facial scan, or other image of you.

When you make a purchase, we ask you to provide payment information, which may include payment card information (such as credit card number, type, and expiration date), vision insurance plan information, billing address, and shipping address. Our payment processor, which is required by credit card issuers to meet specific security requirements, will collect, store, and process your credit card and other payment information on our behalf using industry-standard security measures. We do not store any payment card information.

  *  **When you use MyVisionDirectory.** When you use MyVisionDirectory, you disclose certain personal and health information about yourself, such as your name, contact information, insurance information, billing information, and exam type.

  *  **When you use Prescription Check.** When you use Prescription Check, you disclose certain information about yourself by (1) answering a series of questions to determine whether you are eligible to participate in the Prescription Check vision test (the “Eligibility Questionnaire”), (2) performing a series of tasks to help licensed optometrists or ophthalmologists (each an “Eye Doctor”) determine whether to issue you an updated eyewear prescription (the “Vision Test”), and (3) communicating with Warby Parker or our Eye Doctors in connection with your use of Prescription Check. The In-Store Prescription Check Vision Test includes an acuity test and measurement of your refractive error using a handheld device, and the results of both will be provided to us. 

"Health Information" is information that relates to your past and present health or vision conditions (including medications, ailments, and prescriptions) that is derived from your use of Prescription Check or MyVisionDirectory. Some Health Information may be subject to laws and regulations, including HIPAA. You represent that any Health Information that you disclose to us is your Health Information that you are authorized to disclose to us. “Personal Information” is information about you, including your first name, last name, and demographic information, derived from your use of Prescription Check or MyVisionDirectory. Your Warby Parker account contains Personal Information and/or Health Information, and we will access such information when you use Prescription Check. Additionally, in order to facilitate your use of Prescription Check and to help an Eye Doctor determine your need for an eyewear prescription, we may collect the following information when you use Prescription Check:

    * your name, age, email address, username, or other Personal Information or Health Information contained in your Warby Parker account
    * answers and written information that you submit during the Eligibility Questionnaire
    * your answers to, performance of, and actions taken during the Vision Test 
    * timestamps of all actions that you take within the Prescription Check App
    * Health Information prepared by an Eye Doctor who provides you Services, such as medical records, prescriptions, treatment decisions, medical advice, examination notes, and any other information prepared by an Eye Doctor about your health or vision 
    * billing information that you provide us, such as credit card information
    * any other information that you submit to us in connection with your Eligibility Questionnaire, Vision Test, Prescription Check, or the Services, including information exchanged in emails, texts, chats, or calls between you and Warby Parker.
  *  **When you contact us.** We do everything possible to make sure you have an exceptional shopping experience. If you contact us in person, by phone (calling or texting), email, instant message (including Facebook Messenger), live chat, through social media or our App, or by some other means, we may keep a record of your contact information and the content of the communication for later reference. When we send you emails, we may track whether you open them to learn how to deliver a better customer experience and improve our Services. We receive responses to any survey that you choose to complete for us.

 **Information we collect from third parties:**

  *  **Information from your doctor.** Your doctor may share your prescription information with us in order for us to provide Services or complete your purchase.

  *  **Information from third party services.** Some parts of our Services can be linked to other accounts you have with Third Party Services (“Third Party Accounts”) or you may be able to register for an account on our Services with your Third Party Account. If you connect a Third Party Account to our Services or interact with us through a Third Party Account, we may receive information about you, including your Third Party Account profile information and your photo, and your use of the Third Party Account (for example, if you select a Warby Parker product to purchase through the account). If you mention us through your Third Party Account, we may collect publicly available information and content related to your comment. If you wish to limit the information available to us, you should visit the privacy settings of your Third Party Accounts to learn about your options.

  *  **Information from other third parties.** We may collect information about you from other third parties, including demographic information, and combine this information with other information we collect about you.

 **Information we automatically collect:**

  *  **Web logs and usage information.** We record certain information and store it in log files when you interact with our Services. This information may include device and browser information, internet protocol (IP) address, URLs of referring/exit pages, and search terms.

  *  **Mobile device information.**

    * _In-store Wi-Fi._ When you connect to our in-store Wi-Fi, we receive information about you and your device, including your device’s MAC address, IP address, received signal strength indicator (RSSI), and technical details about your device such as its operating system, device type (including make and model), and technical capabilities. We will also receive information about how you use our Wi-Fi network while you are connected, including the store location, the areas of the store you visit, the names and/or Internet addresses of the websites you visit and the applications you use, and how long you interact with such sites or applications. If your mobile device is configured to search for available Wi-Fi networks, we may receive information about your device even if you choose not to connect to our Wi-Fi services.

    *  _Our Warby Parker App._ When you download and use our Warby Parker App, we receive information from your mobile device, such as IP address, device information, and unique device identifiers. We may also receive information about your precise location from your device, but only if you enable location tracking on your device. We may collect location data when your device is near our in-store systems, even if you are not currently using the app. You may turn off this location tracking at any time in your app settings or by disabling Bluetooth on your device.

    *  _Prescription Check App._ When you use the Prescription Check App, we may collect information about your mobile device, such as IP address, device information, and unique device identifiers, and we may derive your approximate location from your IP address. When you permit the Prescription Check App to access your location through your mobile device settings, we may collect the precise location of your device when the Prescription Check App is running in the foreground or background. Your location information is necessary to confirm your location while using the Prescription Check App, so we can be sure that your results are reviewed by an Eye Doctor licensed in your state.
  *  **Information from cookies and other technologies.** Like most websites, our Services may incorporate technology such as “pixel tags”, “web beacons”, and “cookies” that allow us and our service providers to collect information about your actions on our Services. Our service providers may collect information about your online activities over time and across different online services. Cookies (not to be confused with the sugary morsel) are small files that web servers may place on your computer when you visit a website. You may be able to set your web browser to reject cookies entirely or require that it request permission from you before accepting each new cookie. You can also delete cookies from your web browser once you leave a website.

  *  **Information from in-store technologies.** We may also collect information when you are visiting our stores. Like most retailers, we have in-store video surveillance for security, fraud, and loss prevention purposes. In addition, we analyze videos to help us understand customer behavior and retail traffic within our physical spaces. Our service providers may also collect information about your mobile device from other tracking technologies while you are near or in our stores to help us better understand our customers and how they use our Services.

## 2\. How We Use Your Information

 **Generally.** We primarily use your information to provide and enhance our Services and your experience with Warby Parker. Some ways we may use your information include:

  * to provide, personalize, and improve our products and our Service
  * to facilitate the sale and delivery of your purchases and Home Try-On
  * to confirm, reschedule, or provide other services related to your eye exam
  * to provide you with Prescription Check services
  * to communicate with you, including to respond to your comments or questions, and to send you updates about your order
  * to understand your use of our Services to help us improve the customer experience
  * to provide you information, recommendations, and marketing materials about our products and Services
  * to deliver gift cards in accordance with your instructions
  * for our other internal business purposes

 **Prescription Check.** When you use Prescription Check, we may use your Health Information and Personal Information to determine the vision correction that you need, and for quality assurance, internal testing and analysis, and to make improvements to Prescription Check. We may also use your Health Information and Personal Information to provide customer service to you, to communicate with you about Prescription Check, to respond to your questions, to contact you regarding your Eligibility Questionnaire, Vision Test, or the Services, to remind you to renew your prescription, or to send an Eye Doctor’s prescription, medical records, advice, decisions, or notes to you. We will not license or sell your Health Information or Personal Information to anyone, and will share it only as set forth below. Warby Parker is committed to protecting your privacy and will comply with all laws and regulations applicable to the use and disclosure of your Health Information and Personal Information. If you receive an eyewear prescription as a result of your use of Prescription Check, we will email you a copy of the prescription and add the prescription information to your Warby Parker account, after which it will appear in your account as “[your first name]’s Prescription Check Rx.” If the Eye Doctor determines that you are not eligible for an updated eyewear prescription through Prescription Check, then we will notify you by email and may include additional notes or recommendations from the Eye Doctor.

 **Location.** We may use location information collected from your mobile device to enhance your shopping experience and to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content, as well as to assist us with foot traffic measurement and service improvements in our stores.

 **Photos, Scans, and Images.** When you submit (or grant us permission to take) a photo, facial scan, or other image of you, we don’t share those photos, scans, or images, or any facial data captured in the facial scans, with any third parties, but we may use them as described below:

  * to measure your [pupillary distance](https://www.warbyparker.com/eyewear-a-z#p-pupillaryDistance) and [segment height](https://www.warbyparker.com/eyewear-a-z#s-segmentHeight), and to gather other optical information
  * to map and measure your facial features
  * to address certain problems or concerns you may have with your glasses 
  * to help better understand how our frames fit our customers and provide frame recommendations
  * to provide, personalize, and improve our products and our Service

We don’t store any facial scans submitted through the iPhone X TrueDepth camera.

## 3\. How We Share Your Information

If we share your information, we do so only as described below.

### With vendors

We’ve figured out ways to do a lot of things on our own, but we haven’t quite figured out how to do all of it. We may provide your information to our contractors, agents, and service providers as necessary to enable them to perform certain services for us, including but not limited to:

  * order fulfillment
  * delivery services
  * payment processing
  * vision insurance claim processing
  * account registration
  * website-related services, such as web hosting
  * improvement of website-related services and features
  * maintenance services
  * marketing services
  * data analytics

### With marketing and advertising partners

We may share your information with third parties for their advertising and marketing purposes, which may include sending you direct mail that may interest you. If you prefer that we not share your address with third parties, you can opt out at [https://dmachoice.thedma.org](https://dmachoice.thedma.org/). Some of our third-party advertising partners use cookies and other technologies to collect information about your online activities on our Services and across other online services in order to deliver more relevant advertising when you are using the Services or other websites.

You can learn about how to opt out of receiving personalized website advertisements from our advertising partners who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative or who subscribe to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising by visiting the opt-out sections on the websites of each of those organizations. Links to those sites are below. Note that because your election to opt out is managed through cookies, if you delete these cookies or use a different browser, you will have to make the same selection again.

  * Network Advertising Initiative: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>
  * Digital Advertising Alliance: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>

One of the third party services that we use to track your activity on our Services is Google Analytics. If you do not want Google Analytics to collect and use information about your use of our Services, then you can install an opt-out in your web browser (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>). You also may opt-out from Google Analytics for Display Advertising or the Google Display Network by using Google’s Ads Settings located at <https://www.google.com/settings/ads>. You can also visit your device’s settings or install the AppChoices app to learn more about how you may opt out of receiving personalized ads in mobile Apps.

Another third party service that we use to track your activity on our Services is Adjust Technology. If you do not want Adjust Technology to collect and use information about your use of our Services, you can opt out at <https://www.adjust.com/opt-out/>.

We use Facebook Custom Audiences to deliver advertisements to you on Facebook, and to provide data to us, based on email addresses that we have collected. 

### With your doctor and dispensing optician

We may share your information with your doctor if you’ve asked us to confirm the prescription information you provide us, or if you’ve asked us to obtain your prescription information from your doctor. At your request, we may also share your information with a dispensing optician.

### With Eye Doctors

In connection with Prescription Check, we will share your Health Information and Personal Information with one or more Eye Doctors, who will evaluate the results of your Eligibility Questionnaire and Vision Test. Eye Doctors may be any of the following: Warby Parker employees, Warby Parker independent contractors, employees of a professional corporation, or independent contractors of a professional corporation. Additionally, we will share the information you provide to us through MyVisionDirectory with the Eye Doctor performing your eye exam. In all cases, Eye Doctors are under a contractual obligation to keep your Health Information and Personal Information confidential.

### With your vision insurance carrier

We may share your information with your vision insurance carrier in order to process your claim and so that we receive payment. 

### On an aggregated or de-identified basis

We may share aggregated or de-identified information (which cannot reasonably be used to identify you) with service providers or other third parties. These service providers and third parties may also share with us aggregated or de-identified information that they have independently developed or acquired.

### With business partners we do not control

We may work with other businesses from time to time. These business partners may sell items or provide promotions to you through our Services or theirs. We may also provide products or services to you jointly with our business partners. We will clearly show you when a business partner is associated with your transaction, and we will only share information with them that is related to your transaction.

### In connection with business transfers

If the ownership of all or substantially all of our business changes, or we otherwise transfer assets relating to our business or any of the Services to a third party (such as by merger, acquisition, bankruptcy proceeding, or other change of control transaction), we may transfer or sell your information to the new owner. In such a case, unless permitted otherwise by applicable law, your information would remain subject to this Privacy Policy unless we notify you otherwise. 

### To protect us and others

We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we reasonably believe is necessary to comply with any applicable law, court order, subpoena, legal process, or enforceable governmental request; cooperate with law enforcement; enforce or apply this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Use, and other agreements; detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Warby Parker, our employees, our users, or others.

### With your consent

Except as we’ve stated above, we will notify you before we share your identifiable information with any third parties.

## 4\. Access to Your Information and Choices You Have With Your Warby Parker Account

Through your account settings, you can access, view, and edit the following information you’ve provided to us:

  * name
  * password
  * mailing address
  * billing address
  * email address
  * phone number

You can delete any of the above information, and contact us with questions or concerns about your information, by emailing [privacy@warbyparker.com](mailto:privacy@warbyparker.com). The information you can view, edit, and delete may change as our Services change.

If you decide you don’t want to receive email from us, you can select the “opt out” provision in our communications to unsubscribe, you can email us at [privacy@warbyparker.com](mailto:privacy@warbyparker.com), or you can contact customer support. Unsubscribing will stop you from receiving most types of email communications, but it may not prevent you from receiving emails about orders or transactions you place through our Services or to emails in response to a specific request from you, such as password recovery. If you wish to stop receiving notifications from us on your mobile device, you can update your device settings.

## 5\. California Privacy Rights

If you are a California resident, in addition to awesome weather, you also have the ability to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal information, as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83, we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for their direct marketing purposes and the contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties (under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84). If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to [privacy@warbyparker.com](mailto:privacy@warbyparker.com). We won’t even ask you for a bottle of Napa Valley chardonnay in return (but if you send one, our staff will happily accept).

## 6\. We are Committed to Protecting Your Information

We take the protection of your information very seriously. We understand the sensitivity of (for example) the prescription information you may give us. Therefore, we take many security measures (physical, electronic, and procedural) to help keep your information safe. For example, we limit access to authorized employees and third parties who are under an obligation to keep all such information confidential. Also, we only allow parties to access your identifiable information for permitted business purposes. Unfortunately, even though we use commercially reasonable efforts to protect your information, we cannot guarantee complete security. Any information that you provide to us is done so entirely at your own risk.

## 7\. Children’s Information

We are especially sensitive about children’s information. We do not knowingly allow individuals under the age of 18 to use Prescription Check and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13, in accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). If you are a parent or legal guardian of a minor child, you may use our Services on behalf of such minor child. If you have questions concerning our information practices with respect to children, or if you believe a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information, please email us at [privacy@warbyparker.com](mailto:privacy@warbyparker.com).

## 8\. Not Intended for EU Residents; Information Stored in the United States

The Services are not intended for European Union (EU) residents. Accordingly, you understand that your information may be stored in the United States. Information may be transferred outside of the country where you reside or are located, including to countries that may not or do not provide the same level of protection as the EU. By using and accessing our Services, users who reside or are located in countries outside of the United States agree and consent to the transfer and processing of personal information on servers located outside of the country where they reside, and acknowledge that the protection of such information may be different than required under the laws of their residence or location.

## 9\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We occasionally review this Privacy Policy to make sure it complies with applicable laws and conforms to changes in our business. We may need to update this Privacy Policy, and we reserve the right to do so at any time. If we do revise this Privacy Policy, we will update the “Effective Date” at the top of this page so that you can tell if it has changed since your last visit. Your continued use of our Services constitutes your acceptance of the terms of the Privacy Policy as amended or revised by us from time to time.

## 10\. Contact Us

If you have any questions about viewing or updating your information, this Privacy Policy, or our privacy practices, please contact us at [privacy@warbyparker.com](mailto:privacy@warbyparker.com).
